Creative Commons
starring Mayer and Bettle and now... Flik
So explain to me again why, after knowing you for so long, I had to book a month in advance just to catch up for a coffee...
Going out in public is so hard these days.
What?! Why?
Because I’m famous now. I’m like fully a celebrity and everything. I have fans.
They love me. I can probably get us a free lunch ‘cause I’m so famous.
You are not famous.
Uh huh. My first album, ‘The Best Album in the World,’ has been in the Jamendo popular albums for weeks.
Jamendo?
You never were cool were you? It’s a music download site that lets musicians put their songs out under Creative Commons licences so people can share them.
Which means more people download it, so more people hear it, so more fans for me! If that’s even possible. By the way, if you give me 50 bucks, I’ll autograph your face.
Um...thanks. So does Jamendo use the new extended metadata protocols implemented through the Creative Commons licence generator?
Extenda-whaty-now?!
Why don’t I just show you.
Where have you taken me Mayer!? I hope there are no paparazzi. I’m not wearing my sunglasses.
We’re inside the Creative Commons. Everything here, people can share. Stories, photos, websites, movies, sounds. You can tell; they all have the CC license symbols.
Ooooo. Pretty.
But you’re still in control. See, you can let people use your stuff for non-commercial purposes, or only if they don’t change it, or only if they share with others. And they always have to credit you.
The CC website helps you work out which licence is best for you. And it lets you add information about the thing you are licensing, so that information goes wherever your work goes.
See you can add stuff like your name and how to get in contact with you if they want to do stuff that the licence doesn’t allow.
So my name goes wherever my album does. No matter how many times it’s downloaded?
Yep.
That means that everyone will know my name. Everyone will know my songs. I will achieve world domination!!!
I should probably get a get a crown. Oooh! And a corgi!
Huh what?!
Bettle?!
Flik! What are you doing here?
I’ve almost finished our new film. I just came to find a few final photos from Flickr.
Hey, hey? Who’s this?
This is FLIK, my fan and collaborator.
A few months back I was looking on Jamendo for songs for my school film project. I came across one of Bettle’s which was perfect. So I emailed Bettle and she liked my film so much that we started working together.
Flik’s just finished our new one. We’re gonna premier it on Revver. And we’re gonna make lots of money!!
But don’t you give your stuff away for free?  ????????
Just because we’re letting people use our stuff doesn’t mean we can’t make money off it.
Like on Revver. It’s a video sharing site that puts ads into your video and you get some of the money.  So the more people that watch it, the more money we get.
And that’s why my album is on Jamendo. People can share my music for free under the CC licence, but if they want to use it to make money, say on TV or radio, they need to pay. The site lets them do that.
And there are lots of other sites that let you make money off your CC works.
Pretty soon, everyone will use our stuff. Every film, every advertisement, every home DVD. I will be rich. They’ll all scream my name. The world will be mine. MINE!!!
How about we just take it one step at a time hey?
I completely agree, Flik. Hey Mayer…
Yes Bettle?
You owe me 50 bucks.