From my youthful times, from my youthful times
do I hear a song so dear.
How remote the times, how remote the times
that were once so near!
What the swallow sang, what the swallow sang,
heralds fall and spring,
along the village, along the village,
it is still heard?
When I left from there, When I left from there,
trunk and coffer were heavy.
When I came back, when I came back,
all was empty.
No swallow brings, no swallow brings
back to you, what you are longing for.
but the swallow sings, but the swallow sings
in the village as before.
From my youthful times, from my youthful times
do I hear a song so dear
How remote the times, how remote the times
that were once so near!